Dunlap Family Papers WLU.Coll.0245
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Dunlap Family Papers
Inclusive 1830-1878
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Dunlap, John Matthew
Dunlap, John M., Jr
WLU.Coll.0245
17 Files
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John M. Dunlap, Jr. (March 1996)
Scope and Contents
Papers contain information about Dunlap's family members, especially Madison Dunlap (1808-1883) of Kerr's Creek and his son, John Matthew Dunlap, a member of the Washington and Lee Class of 1857 who was killed at at the Battle of Gettysburg in 1863. The collection includes compositions that John Matthew Dunlap wrote for Professor J. J. White in 1856-1857, transcripts of letters he wrote while serving in the Confederate Army, and letters concerning his death. The collection also includes the manuscript of J. D. Morrison's Old Monmouth and Its Times.
College Students; Virginia -- Kerr's Creek; Manuscripts; Records; Receipts (Acknowledgments); Correspondence; Dunlap, Madison; Dunlap Family; Washington College (Lexington, Va.); Dunlap, John M., Jr; White, James J. (James Jones)
- Miscellaneous Bill, 1874; Dunlap, John M., Jr; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Bills, Private
- Genealogical Information, Dunlap, Walter Hanna; 3 Item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  The file includes a 'Family group sheet' on Elizabeth McDowell and Thomas Benton. It also includes data on 'The Wilsons and Moores of Rockbridge County, Virginia,' collected by Walter Hanna Dunlap and on 'Four Preachers.'
  Benton, Elizabeth McDowell; Benton, Thomas Hart
- John M. Dunlap, Bill, 1860; 2 Item (Box 1, Folder 4)
  This collection consists of a bill to John M. Dunlap, Jr. from Anderson. It also consists of an accompanying letter.
  Bills of sale; Dunlap, John M., Jr
- John M. Dunlap, Transcripts of Civil War Letters, 1861-1863; Dunlap, Walter Hanna (Box 1, Folder 5)
  This file consists of transcripts of letters from John Matthew Dunlap to his brother Bill, from John to his family, from Dr. B. Greenlee to John M. Dunlap, Jr., from Samuel Mckee Laird, and from Charles F. Jordan, Captain Co. C of the 1st Regiment Va. Calvary.
  Dunlap, John Matthew; Dunlap, William Madison
- Compositions, by student Washington College student John McKee Dunlap, 1856-1857; Dunlap, John Matthew; 3 Item (Box 1, Folder 6)
  This file consists of three manuscript compositions written by Washington College student John Mckee Dunlap for Professor James Jones (J.J.) White titled, 'An Evening Adventure' - about a walk to and about the Liberty Hall Academy ruin, 'Eloquence', and 'Fashion'.
  White, James J. (James Jones)
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1830-1840; 5 Item (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Bills of sale; Dunlap, Madison
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1840-1850; 18 Item (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1850-1855; 24 Item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Dunlap, Madison
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1856-1859; 20 Item (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1860-1870; 9 Item (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Madison Dunlap, Accounts, 1870-1878; 10 Item (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Madison Dunlap, Bills, Receipts, Promissory Notes, 1845-1877; 19 Item (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Promissory notes; Receipts (Acknowledgments); Dunlap, Madison
- Madison Dunlap, Tax Receipts, 1835-1868; 26 Item (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Contains receipts and transcript
- Manuscript of "Old Monmouth and its Times" by J. D. Morrison, 14 Item (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Manuscripts
- Transcript of "Old Monmouth and its Times", 1996-05-01; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Transcribed by John M. Dunlap, Jr. of Waynesboro, Va.
- Scotch-Irish History - Transcripts of Articles, Creation of transcription; 1895-06-27; Waddell, Joseph Addison; Rockbridge County News; McLaughlin, William; 2 Item (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Rockbridge County News